JOSE CHANDY (1) Featured

Seeking roles in Software Engineering, Software Development, Web Application Development, Application Support, Project Management, Change Management, Quality Management, Requirement Gathering, Ruby Rails, JavaScript, Bootstrap, React. Js, iQuery, Oracle, MySQL



Current Designation: Team Leader Total Experience: 10 Year(s) 0 Month(s)

Current Company: Behealthe Technologies Notice Period: 1 Month

Current Location: Changnacherry Highest Degree: B.Tech/B.E. [Computers]

Pref. Location: Bengaluru / Bangalore, Chennai, Hyderabad Functional Area: IT Software - Application Programming /

Maintenance

Role: Software Developer

Industry: IT-Software/Software Services

Marital Status: Single/unmarried

Key Skills: CTO, Software Developer, Software Engineering, Software Development, Web Application

Development, Application Support, Project Management, Change Management, Quality Management, Requirement

Gathering, Ruby Rails, JavaScript, Bootstrap, React. Js, ¡Query, Oracle, SQL

Verified: Email - id Phone Number |

Last Active: 22-Jan-21 Last Modified: 22-Jan-21

Summary

10 years of experience in web application development. 5+ years of working as the CTO of a startup, responsible for designing, building and supporting the application . Hands on experience on both server side and front end technologies.

Work Experience

Behealthe Technologies as Team Leader May 2015 to Till Date

behealthE is aimed at providing realtime queue status to patients for their OP consultations. Was responsible for designing and implementing the web and mobile application. Worked on technologies like ruby on rails, react, react-native, bootstrap and mysql Worked on google cloud platform

Citi Corp as Assistant Manager Dec 2013 to May 2015

RDM is developed as a part of new platform/application knows as CitiRisk Commercial. This is the unified platform used by Citi Commercial Bank business and risk to implement the common lending process across all commercial bank countries. This powerful application is used to reduce operational costs, improve data quality, and render a quick turnaround time for customers. It integrates over 19 modules to support business/sales, risk and operation related functions. CitiRisk Commercial leverages all Citi

gold data sources, including AMC, DSMT, and Optima, thus enabling a more effective and efficient system for Citi clients worldwide.

This industry-leading consolidated system enables the commercial bank to digitally manage the end-to-end credit approval process across business and risk, thus offering the benefits of efficiency and process standardization across all global rollout countries.. Worked on technologies like j2ee, juice and hibernate.

Egain Communications as Software Engineer 2 Aug 2011 to Dec 2013

eGain (NASDAQ: EGAN) is the leading provider of cloud and on-site customer interaction hub software. For over a decade, eGain solutions have helped improve customer experience, optimize service process and grow sales-across the web, social, and phone channels. Every year they release a product with more features and enhancement as eGainxx.eGain11 consist Mail, Chat, Click2Call, CallTrack, Offers, Social, Cobrowse, Self-service, Analytics ext as different channels to interact with customers. Working in the development of the eGain suite which is a software used by companies for interactions with their customers I work on features and bugs presented to me in the application which is a J2EE application include front end JSPs and Servlets classes to communicate with the backend DBs(Oracle and MSSQL). Has hands on experience on HTML and Javascript Good exposure on upgrade-installer and installer frameworks of our application Worked on installer framework softwares (InstallAnywhere/InstallShield) Has hands on experience in analyzing Thread dumps and Heap dumps Has exposure to JMS Has hands on experience of TSQL and PL/SQL Worked on application servers like Jboss and Weblogic Worked on web servers like Apache and IIS

Education

UG: B.Tech/B.E. (Computers) from National Institute of Technology (NIT), Calicut in 2010

IT Skills

Skill Name	Version Last Used Experience
J2ee, Ruby, Bootstrap, Jquery	
Javascript, React.js, Mysql	
Oracle, MSSQL, Java	

Languages Known

Language	Proficiency	Read	Write	Speak
English				

Affirmative Action

Physically Challenged: No

Work Authorization

Job Type: Permanent / Temporary

Employment Status: Full Time, Part Time